              Content                          Knowledge 
             Integration                       Construction
      Content integration deals with     Teachers need to help students 
      the extent to which teachers use   understand, investigate, and 
      examples and content from a        determine how the implicit 
      variety of cultures in their       cultural assumptions, frames of 
      teaching.                          reference, perspectives, and 
                                         biases within a discipline 
                                         influence the ways in which 
                                         knowledge is constructed.



         Equity                                       Prejudice 
        Pedagogy                                      Reduction
An equity pedagogy exists when                 This dimension focuses on the 
teachers modify their teaching in              characteristics of students' 
ways that will facilitate the Multicultural    racial attitudes and how they 
academic achievement of        Education       can be modified by teaching 
students from diverse racial,                  methods and materials.
cultural, gender, and social-class 
groups.



                              Empowering 
                             School Culture

                      Grouping and labeling practices,
                      sports participation, disproportionality 
                      in achievement, and the interaction 
                      of the staff and the students across 
                      ethnic and racial lines must be
                      examined to create a school culture 
                      that empowers students from diverse 
                      racial, ethnic, and gender groups.

